all right
[Music]
welcome it's October 17th 2023 and we're
in our first discussion of chapter 8 in
cohort 4 so to begin with what are just
any thoughts or
memories that you fellows have about
chapter
8 just any any piece that you remember
or anything about
eight um I was curious about the part
where they talk about how movement and
attenuation like sensory attenuation
that was interesting to me where they I
hope I remember calling this correctly
but it was like you didn't want to
perfectly predict it at a certain point
for
like to perceive movement which was
interesting um I don't know if I
perfectly understand that but uh I kind
of see an intuitive aspect to that I
guess oh yeah that's a very interesting
section Andrew anything that that
you um think about yeah yeah um I guess
I'd second an interest in sensory
attenuation as well because I I guess um
we could get to that but like box 8.1 is
kind of the key bit of interest there
the relationship between Precision
attention and sensory attenuation so
they seem to more or less equate
precision and
attention um I guess the idea is um you
have some kind of belief that is you
know I am not moving and you need you
need to downplay or decrease the
Precision of that
belief such that you can actually move
in the first place otherwise if you have
very high Precision I am not
moving um that kind of stays in place
and so you never actually get started on
moving um yeah know I thought that was
really interesting and it comes up a
little bit more later in the chapter on
how that kind of plays out and the
movement of Limbs and such so I thought
that was pretty pretty
fascinating yeah totally and like where
else does that apply like can we
understand the example they give with a
motor
Behavior connected to the Octan fonty
and then what other
analogous um sensory attenuation cases
might be happening let's just see if
it's been explored in a
question
okay we'll definitely look at this
question about
precision and then here's the Box
8.1
okay no
answer what what what's interesting
about
it um a or what what would you want to
know about it or what do I mean um I
guess like I was just it was just
something where
um when I read it it
was it
made uh sense but I'm still trying
to let me see if I can find
it it made sense it was just
um interesting
that we aren't like was it were they
saying that the perception of movement
itself like in order to perceive
movement it was like we were decreasing
how um well we were
predicting uh those States
yeah in order to generate Movement we
must be able to ignore the sensory
consequences which is to say dis attend
to it or attenuate to it yeah of that
move movement to form the initially
false belief that I am
moving okay
okay yeah that's like just I don't know
something about that's very interesting
it's
a
so and then afterwards are you we are
trying to make up for that
by uh trying
to predict those uh or get those
appropriate like inferences right um
it's not you're not you're you're going
to start attending to it again or is it
you just decrease how much attention
you're putting on to those States at
first and then after
you're yeah
make certainly it's an oscillatory
pattern so one one analogy or another
case or sensory tenation is really
important is the ey Cade so when the
Eyes Are Fixed the Precision is is high
so that changes in the visual scene when
the Eyes Are Fixed can be informative
and then during head movement Andor eye
movement you kind of have like a a hyper
prior that pixel changes or or um are
uninformative because they're they're
not going to be very useful there's
You're Expecting High volatility on when
there's movement so during that there
like a sensory attenuation during the
seccade and then as soon as the Cade
ends it's just like re-engages attenion
okay so it's kind of like when when the
um when the signal to contract the bicep
occurs there's also a descending
relaxation of the tricep in in the kind
of healthy setting so it's not just like
pull on one side and pull on the other
side it's like a joint contraction and
relaxation signal that that's happening
with two opponent
muscles whereas the icade attenuation
example is more like opponent processing
with a motor and an attention variable
but they they alternate
okay so we have the isoc case with
visual perception getting out of a chair
well and there probably are other
differences here
like you could argue whether the
iade
cons it's kind of like it's considering
the
counterfactual um just like the getting
out of the chair
is I am not in a chair is the
counterfactual the iade counterfactual
is like I am looking over
there but you're
not
and so the the um distri the belief
distribution um ultimately you want to
shift your location in that
space But if the um current Precision
around the current state estimate
doesn't have significant Mass covering
that
counterfactual then it it can't be
switched over to so sensory attenuation
relaxes the
attention expands the variance reduces
the Precision makes it so it's like
instead of like 99% sure that it's this
way go well it's 80% sure that it's this
way 20% that it's that way that opens
the door to the counterfactual being
realized through action just to kind of
restated a bunch of ways because I
think if it is the case that that's how
um attention and attenuation work then
probably it's going to be prevalent in
like
every sensory motor
system because the alternative would be
constant
Precision yeah and then would so
constant Precision would make it would
actually make you less likely
to um be able to process movement
because there's a lot of
uh it's almost like you're be able like
less likely to get new information is
that kind of a way of thinking about it
is that why we're kind of relaxing the
attention so we could be more flexible
with sort of uh states that are changing
very
rapidly I think that's true so let's
think about what would happen if you had
constant Precision constant Precision to
your visual field in iade or constant
Precision to your proprioception for the
getting out of the chair case well when
your eyes were um
moving just where would you fix your
constant value if you fixed it at the
level of that that your surprise should
be at for being fixed then it'll be
shocking when there's movement if you
have it when it is if you um calibrate
to when the pixels are moving a lot then
you won't be able to glean as much
information when they're not moving
because you'll be dis attending or you
could pick a lukewarm value and kind of
blend those two be a little bit more
surprised than you should be when it's
surprising and then a little bit less
informative when your gaze is fixed so
obviously an approach to resolve this
tension is to have oscillation or some
kind of
conditional
attention so that you can tune it and do
the best you can do in each moment
instead of trying to like fix a
value when we already know that there's
a different
optimal Precision for
different um settings or like with
through time within the same
setting
okay
that makes sense it's kind of like
a uh trying to think of
a good sort of analogy but uh just like
you're actually doing worse by it's kind
of like you know you're grasp in like
have you ever heard of that analogy
where you're grasping like a seed you
can't hold too hard
or it'll like slip out but if you hold
it too loose it'll also slip out so you
need to like
adjust yeah that's that's good
connection that's also related to kind
of optimal
grasp like Optimal grasp on a pen is not
the maximum compress Force for for a
variety of reason you know you'd be
exhausted you couldn't have um dextrous
movement or something like that so like
then that's related to like not over
under
fitting and that's kind of the
VF imperative which is you want to fit a
distribution given the family of
variational distributions that you're
choosing
from gaussian or whatever it is you want
to parameterize it so that if you were
to make it any tighter you'd be
overfitting and then if you made it any
looser you would be having left
information that you could have used so
it's on some trade-off
Frontier um which we can be along with a
KL Divergence so it's like a it's you
know it's in a good spot and it's on a
good optimizable
manifold that if the variational family
is at all
appropriate
you're going to get to the optimal grasp
now maybe it's like um trying to do
optimal grasp on something that's too
small or too large to be grasped that
would be like if the distribution family
was
inappropriate then you'd You' come to
the best grasp you could of you know the
mountain but you there you it wouldn't
be possible to actually do it so that
kind of con actually like the the the
model that doesn't under overfit still
may have an adequacy of
1% given the data and all this other
things MH and then and then one other
connection there is like um the Colman
filter or just generalized filtering so
we're getting measurements from the
thermometer Through Time one or more
thermometers through time and then we're
tracking the temperature
distribution um or stock prices or
something then you want to be tracking
both the expected mean temperature and
the variance like the volatility or just
the
uncertainty the the sort of fundamental
uncertainty or volatility and then also
the measurement Associated so the
measurement Associated volatility is
more like a
matrix the actual Dynamics are more like
B but and so but to whatever extent it
comes the noise or the variability comes
from either the sensor measurements or
the underlying dynamics of the
system you you want to be fitting this
curve Through
Time such that new noisy data
measurements are not like falling
outside the curve because then that's
more surprising than it should be then
you should wide to the curve or um if
all the data are falling like within the
plus or minus one standard deviation on
the curve then you could have done
better by tightening the
distribution son's work on the
generalized filtering is really nice on
this on the the generalized
filtering kind of connecting into the
the
Baye
um basing optimal filtering in
perception and then bringing in action
this also kind of reminds me of uh
exploration exploitation tradeoff and
reinforcement learning and uh soft value
functions where they actually instead of
just trying to optimize a reward they
try to also increase the entropy like an
entropy value um so which seems kind of
counterintuitive but it's actually
performs really well it makes it very
flexible and able to deal with
protuberances specifically so like
disturbances like a if you have a robot
that's trying to work in an environment
where things can start disturbing it and
things like that having sort of that
like trying to optimize that entropy
value as well as the reward value makes
it so it can actually adjust and uh deal
with disturbances a lot better which
kind of reminds me of like movement also
it's kind of like disturbances to
sort of
your oh yeah yeah and uh there's two
kinds of motor disturbances ones you
have agency over and ones you don't have
agency over which ones are more
surprising the ones you don't have
agency over like um you can um not a
recommendation but you can slightly push
the eye so that it's kind of like a non
seccade induced visual shift of course
that's surprising um or if uh you can't
tickle yourself because the expected
propri acceptive consequences of
tickling
yourself
are not attended to because they're
expected so they're
confirmed um
or yeah
just how we expect H how far do we
expect the stair to
be if it's a little bit more or less
then it's surprising so then just the
expected consequences of
action are normalized
too I mean Sensations are
perceived calibrated to what their
expected states are this is kind of the
whole predictive
processing everything is is is like
sensory attenuation is kind of a
Cory
of um a first principles
corollary of this kind of action and
perception as
inference and then it just like um uh
predictive coding in the visual
system this is empirically
found in different systems and then and
then it'd be interesting like what other
phenomena
are like where do we see allostasis or
attenuation
in um in other systems like if you
have um the bacteria and the gradient of
sugar or like antibiotics or something
it recalibrates
to the value with like a kind of log
sensitivity so that it can always have
optimal grasp on making a
decision about the gradient if the
gradient were a thousand times longer
than the
bacteria it couldn't detect it if the
gradient was a millionth of the
wavelength of a bacteria it couldn't
detect it but then there's some range
that it can actually do the
calibration that gives the most
statistical
resolution just like the aperture of a
camera or the noise level of a
sensor and so then when you're
calibrating the microphone or the the
whatever it is the two
kind of two minimal things or the one
minimal thing is just the
mean that or that's like the Delta the
dero Delta function is if you can only
estimate one parameter about to
calibrate the microphone in the room you
would want to know the potentially the
average or the mean of the
median
volume and then the second thing would
be a variance
parameter um those might be jointly
estimated for certain one parameter
families of
distributions like Pon
distribution where you only use one
parameter to describe the
family and then that is like where like
the mean and the variance are equal is a
one
parameter
estimation but in other case the kind of
two that are helpful are the central
tendency
and then the variance it doesn't have to
be gaussian but you kind of need those
two because if you don't have a measure
of this of a central
tendency and then how wide a field of
the central
tendency then it's like you're kind of
saying that it's a
diverging
situation so then it's not really
identifiable good good stats
pieces all of regular these are common
topics and in other
statistics
settings and it's kind of cool because
like they're often discussed in the
signal
processing inbound passive inference
side common filter all the variational
auto encoder and then also in in a kind
of slightly siloed
way in the control theory
optimal control K optimal control
way so then those two
statistical problems can be understood
as kind of like two
complimentary special cases there's
optimal signal processing when you have
no agency or no action control and then
there's optimal control in a completely
known
environment where there's no epistemic
value which is like the figure from
earlier with showing expected free
energy and then when certain things are
included or not what special cases
results so sensory
attenuation it's a
useful tractable
Motif that does
that that uh addresses the
the the kind of realistic statistical
problems by modulating and
[Music]
learning
attention another thing I was uh curious
about was the generalized synchrony um
where they're talking about the birds um
doing the bird song and then the the
other one would try to finish the other
segments of the song it just kind of
started going into uh something I'm like
uh been interested in which is like
communication and uh even like
Linguistics and
just like how that seems similar to
communicating language and like when you
talk to like a language model you're
like people a lot of people say it's
just predicting sort of the the best
response or what's the most likely next
response um and it kind of just remind
me reminded me of like this generalized
synchrony where the birds are singing
the song and then the next segment of
the song would be sort of it's kind of
like a response almost to the other bird
if there's like two birds singing
um yeah I guess I was just like Curious
in like how
that and communication works like is
this like the very most basic form of
communicating in active inference like
between two sorts of Agents
uh
like yeah yeah good
questions
Andrew oh yeah I just wanted
to I uh previously skimmed a paper by
friston and Par and they actually
reference it here at the bottom of
165 um it they built another model that
basically has two agents you know
communicating with one another and with
synchrony I I'd rather go with the bird
song example I guess since it's more top
of mine but um I it's just it's rather
fascinating there's this um described
like the birds are basically learning
one
another's model parameters right such
that they start making virtually the
same inferences you know one is with the
other um I think this is a wonderful
kind of example too because I can
imagine two musicians you know wanting
to play the same song staying in time
with one another kind of following the
same script or sheet music um but yeah
I'll I'll try to find that that paper
just because I think it's if you're if
you find interest in it it's you know
it's more based on potentially what
humans would be doing um it includes the
entire model of like how do you you know
how do you construct um in communication
like what is a question um what are the
different states uh involved with
questions asking one another questions
answering questions and and like so I'd
love to check that out yeah yeah that's
cool yeah you even said like scripts and
uh Alber Ro n all with the strong and
weak scripts so you have two musicians
it could be they could literally have
the same sheet music and that could be
truly isomorphic sheet music like
they're both playing the first trumpet
part on this one song the same time it
could also be a general synchrony which
is to say not necessarily a lock step
maybe it's a call and response so
there's still a perfect Mutual
information between the two sheet music
readings that are ongoing even though
they might be playing different
instruments or they might be playing
different parts so that's like what in
that bird song example and subsequently
they've referred to as like the singing
from the same hym
sheet and then kind of stepping out into
the Improv is another step that I know
some music and other researchers are are
interested in
because like with questions or other um
turn-taking mechanisms because obviously
it's different when there's epistemic
transfer in
communication of of whatever kind versus
just the
co- performance of something that's
fixed ahead of time so that's that's one
key piece and then um the uh the point
about the large language models is a is
a really good one so the the likeliest
continuation
of this trained model it's almost like
the current token is y That's the
observation and then we have like Q big
foundation model Q now it's not
necessarily a variational basian model
but then there's going to be some
variational free energy landscape and
then when the temperature is low it
picks simply the next
likeliest outcome
and then when the as the temperature
increases you flatten that landscape so
it starts sampling like more
broadly to to the point of breaking out
of kind of semantic ruts but decreasing
potentially like the fluency or the
coherence so that that's like we have
the path of least action and then we
have that temperature or shaky hand
parameter because in language selection
of topic and sentence and word and phon
name and all of that is like this nested
policy selection
task and then so we have both the um
path of least action that's kind of the
ridge on the bottom of the valley and
then we have this like sampling
technique where you can sample along the
strictest um likeliest path of
continuation or you can
sample more broadly like from that
Valley so it's an example of how like
statistics or otive inference approaches
could be taken even if GPT 4 whatever
doesn't need to be applying active
inference from the
inside but we could still talk about its
expectations or
preferences and how that conditions its
actions and all these different
aspects but it's map not territory so
we'll be doing like cognitive mapping of
gp4 not not reverse engineering or
engineering from the
inside so the bird song
example is a singing from the same hym
Sheet
example where there's an expected and so
it's an interesting and a good good uh
continuation from the sensory
attenuation they both have this an
expectation in their gener each bird in
in its generative model of how the song
ised to
go and then the question is are they
going to be singing that
song or not and so in this example it's
like well like someone should be singing
it this way and then it finds itself
singing and then as it continues to sing
takes its
turn its um Precision
drops we we could talk about why
Precision might drop through time and
then eventually that leads to a uh
consideration hey maybe maybe I'm not
the one continuing this
song and then that's like the kind of
turn-taking mechanic but it's not the
only turn-taking mechanic that you could
design you could use like a stop you
know word like over or something like
that or start words or all you know you
can you can make any mechanism and then
I think they show in that first paper
with frisen frii or in some other papers
like maybe what one have you mentioned
about like the learning of the model and
in that case there was like a younger
bird like a more plastic bird with low
precision and then over multiple rounds
it leared how the song was supposed to
be and then the first bird was taken
away and then the new one was added in
and they showed that basically you could
do like this successive
passaging of
entrainments in the generalized
synchrony
setle so they mentioned like this leads
to the Birds trying to like match their
internal models um by trying to match
how they continue
singing um and I was I mean I definitely
want to check out like how it was like
all of this was like how fren and all of
them connected this to
communication um because like I guess
I'm like wondering like how you
communicate bits of
information uh directly
because like it makes sense you match
the internal models and then
you uh I guess like you take turns and
you communicate the next
section and
then I guess what it informs the other
bird just like from like a sort of based
like information Theory type
uh perspective it's like now the other
bird knows that they're singing the same
song um um I guess that is like some
information that's being communicated
and
then um yeah it's like matching the same
song and then I
guess uh I guess that is kind of like an
analog for language if you consider
every idea or concept a song and you're
trying to match with the same concept
ccept or like some communication that
you're trying to
communicate I think there's some some I
was just gonna say I think there's some
some Theory somewhere I don't want to
misquote someone I think it was from a
neuroscientist
uh um but uh the idea that whenever two
people are communicating it seems to be
the case that including using like
neurophysiological measures like EEG or
otherwise that there tends to be an
increasing kind of synchrony between
them um that includes in the in the kind
of spectral Dimension like frequency um
like if you did like a spectral
decomposition of the EEG and look at the
frequencies going on like their their
frequencies tend to slowly begin to
match one another um and furthermore if
you kind of analyze the contents of the
conversation which I'm not quite sure
how you do this with high Precision
mathematically but um the idea is like
two people communicating with each other
are slowly reaching some kind of
convergence or consensus in what the
conversation is about um about
agreements upon the topic even if you
disagree at some point you do converge
in the idea of well now I know your
stance and I also know my stance so at
least that kind of Truth has been
converged upon so I guess to Summit up
like communication is some kind of
General uh process of of convergence or
syy of of information of brain
frequencies um and I guess I guess here
with um chapter eight uh synchron
synchronization of chaos because I guess
we haven't really gotten into that but
like using the Lauren system as one
potential like continuous model as
well sharing all
that that reminds me of like how
communic a in uh like Wolf's ruad is
sort of like between observers is kind
of explained it was like uh between The
Observers they have like shared like
segments of the ruad um that they could
both like kind of agree upon
um which kind of reminds me of sort of
like trying to match your internal model
or you know like what you were saying
like at least you converge that you both
or or some understanding even if it's on
an agreement it's like you're converging
on how your stance is related to the
other person's stance where like that
relationship itself is kind of like a
concept on its own
um which is very interesting it's like
we each we we're putting both of our
cards on the table now we can see each
other's cards so to speak like that
information has not been shared um right
even if the information that you brought
to the table uh was different uh right
now you've kind of come together here
you have shared information and
furthermore you are in the an instance
of a particular conversation right so
it's yeah
yeah and like in information Theory like
communication channels um it's kind of
like um you're trying to it I mean a lot
of this chapter reminded me a lot of
communication channels from information
Theory just like trying to know what the
original input was that goes across a
channel and then you get an output but
the output might not be the same as the
input and you have to see if it matches
and if it's if there's noise then there
might be some variation with the output
so it's just kind of like trying to
decrease that noise and then that's why
you calculate the capacity of what's
sort of the max rate of bits you could
communicate across this channel without
sort of um where you know for a fact
that um you'll be able to map it
directly to sort of the original input
or like the
cause so yeah a ton of great connections
I think it's gonna be really exciting to
see the quantum
FP Chris Fields semantic information
flow meet up with wolf from ruad I think
that should be impending and but um yeah
and then there's kind of like the the
agent environment communication that's
Alice and
Bob and then sometimes we can kind of
take the um Alice as agent environment
as agent Bob as agent and then just sort
of like summarize it with just a
holographic screen with the classical
information which is like saying that
there's an
inert uh intermediating entity so
Quantum on either side of the boundary
and classical or n dimensional on the
boundary and then n plus dimensions on
the in the
quantum
[Music]
um and then there's uh simpler examples
too like having a bunch of metronomes on
a table so if the table is
fixed and then there can't be like force
transduction amongst the
metronomes they will continue unabated
with whatever population distribution is
initiated and then if there is coupling
nonzero coupling then like that's the
kind of famous videos where they enter
into lockstep they're simple or
conservative active
things so the general synchrony that
they come to is like
either all aligned or a two-phase but
then I've also seen it where it's
two-phase and then it kind of Falls a
little bit off and then it actually
slides all the way to back to lock step
because that's a slightly more
favorable synchrony but they're all
exact versus one where say it's like
5050 or 991 with one going in the
counter phas so that's kind of like the
simplest generalized
synchrony and then it's a huge open
topic with semantics and
Linguistics seems like there's a lot of
information in the sequences of
tokens how many bits how many knots
relative to what but also it's not just
the sequence of tokens we know that in
our generation of language and our
seemingly our perception that of course
the
timing tone context all these other
features come into play so then what is
their Mutual
information and there's settings where
maybe just the tokens are necessary and
sufficient there's another situation
where the Tok there might not even be a
token like a silent sign what does that
say so then yeah these are great
questions of communication I think we'll
continue to see like in a lot of
different
fronts like ratcheting of the okay now
sophisticated and the affective and and
then they have these models of the
nested look at this this is like figure
4.3 identical on top and then the
bottom whereas in figure 4.3 in the
textbook the bottom is the continuous
time
GM here we see the discrete time GM
converted um into the for Factor
graph and that supports the message
passing more approximately but but we're
dealing with this exact same discreete
time model and then as we see with like
the folk psychology models often the
more cognitive or symbolic tasks are
discreet and then the hybrid model is
like where it hits the ground it's
continuous like for example um the
larynx um contraction or voice box or
lip or tongue might be a continuous time
continuous actuation model so you have
some continuous
um um voice
apparatus with a propri reception and
the actuation making phonemes but then
once you're in the space of identifiable
phonemes um or
lexim then you can be at this level
where they're now making discrete
time
models at the symbolic so they've
abstracted away from the phon they're
not de with that here I'm saying that's
that's kind of implicitly underneath it
they're just saying that that they
discreetly
produce and
recognize these
words but then that's what's so nice
about the composability of ACM okay now
here they're taking it deep we see that
four3 but now there's each time step has
three nested so that's discreete with
Indiscreet nesting and then you could
also um just say instead of the
observation being a discret
token you could plug in a continuous
model
there and then you can evaluate you know
empirically or what are the
computational requirements or where is
it where you getting more um value
at and I think well the chaos thing
that's explored a lot in the uh
stochastic chaos and marov blankets
paper I think 34 live stream
34 and then it's interesting how like
even though a lot and I think Thomas par
may have remarked on this in the book
stream 2.1
like the earliest ACM models were the
continuous
time and then to
accommodate classically symbolic
cognitive processes and also explicit
planning as inference
and also to to integrate with a
PDP well known in planning there was a
movement towards the
discret and then there's theost at all
2020 like a synthesis of active
inference in discreet State spaces so
not like it's like finished and people
continue to develop new motifs and
discrete compositions but kind of like
the fundamentals of the
discret were then focused on more and
then potentially now with the path-based
formulation of basian
mechanics G Theory everything that
Dalton and Maxwell at all are working
on there's kind of like a a a a
renewed emphasis and generalization on
continuous structures like paths sheath
bundles
topos things that the book book doesn't
necessarily go into but sets the stage
for and then figure 8.6 kind of like
um shows in the simplest possible
example which is the same one that live
stream 46 the ACM does not contradict
folk psychology the simplest hybrid
model where you have a
discreet higher level
symbolic um Dimension and then this kind
of like sensory motor continuous time so
this is like figure 4.3 get smooshed
together and then yeah I mean just in
terms of the location in the
book second half is the
more
pragmatic uh
model you know construction and
implementation based Focus starting with
chapter six with the
recipe um and then just like the low and
the high road were sort of this
dialectic that that are unified or
contained you know of or by active
inference in seven and8 we have that
distinction and then again with with
this figure
8.6 by the end of chapter eight we're
already landed with the synthesis of
seven and eight whereas two and three
they really are like different branches
and they meet in the middle in seven and
eight it's more like I mean they're
just tucked together at the end of
eight and then chapter nine introduces
okay well what if instead of of
specifying a GM hasht chapter 6 and then
generating synthetic data what if we
already had collected data of a certain
structure we knew that we were going to
collect data of a certain structure how
could we then prepare a GM that would
recognize that data allow us to do
statistics on it whether we do discret
continuous or Hybrid models chapter nine
and then the end of the
book so it's just like so funny how
second half starts fast
describes a few key here's the
vertebrates here's the invertebrates or
or whatever uh here's the kingdom of the
fungi here's the other
Kingdom then chapter nine gets more
empirically
oriented and chapter
10 simply reviews and contextualizes
active
inference so it's a quick
ride it is very fast
yeah let's just see what the other
questions were how is five figure 52
related to figure 84
52 hierarchical predictive processing
84 luren
synchronization we should we should
procedurally generate every single
possible question how is everyone every
every figure I
mean um I mean for a for a brief second
I thought maybe it would related it to 8
figure 8.1 which is a little more I
don't know um not quite message passing
but at least it's you know we're still
in the realm of looking at error
terms basically these these basic
equations with
Lauren's to go with Lauren's systems
though and relating that to message
passing um I'm not sure I'm not so sure
there's no clear there's no yeah no
where my brain quickly
goes well that's the
attenuated space where any account could
be possible or more accounts could be
possible
like again to this kind of question
prompt question answer or even hegelian
problem reaction solution structure it's
interesting like which questions just
have an
answer which ones are like the Grand
Canyon where the continuation there
should only be like one specific
continuation like what's the
relationship between policy and
affordance there may be a formal
answer not even to say that that would
be the only answer still
but there might be a Sumo
expressable necessary sufficient answer
which is like pretty good but then for
for for any question but especially some
of
them these questions are basically just
evocative which is totally fine I think
it's
fun we're only going to experience even
just with a 30 or 50 or how many figures
there are I mean that would be like
200 questions
MH so so just like then so that's the
epistemic foraging which question should
we
ask prompt
engineering conversation
Theory all these different things
like folding back into
our the way that we're learning
active like okay now that we've looked
at what are the causes and consequences
of sensory
attenuation now what are we going to pay
more or less attention to or now that
we've talked about communication along
these
lines then how do we do
what lot of fun options
there here's the improvisation
question yeah
I'll just move it to this
one
any any uh last
thoughts um yeah so in chapter nine is
it more about like using active
inference on sorts of like if you wanted
to use it on like a data set to detect
something or you know things like
that um yeah basically it points that
way it is not the guide book or the
Google collab notebook or whatever that
just oh yeah load in your CSV and then
this is just going to analyze the data
for you so it's not to that point but
what I think nine does that's important
first
9.1 is a schema of the behavioral
scientific setting where you have a
behavioral science laboratory making a
cognitive model of the rat or the ant or
whatever which might be a map back of
the environment but it frames it in a
way that we can handle with ACM and
then analogous to how chapter six gave a
recipe for making the GM figure
92 gives us the road map from going from
the data plus the
GM to basically the kind of figure that
would be in a published
paper like we proposed um a personality
variable or a psychometric variable of
this kind continuous or discreet or
whatever it
was we had the generative model we had
these data and likelihood function we
inverted the model in light of our prior
beliefs which might be uniform across
groups or how whatever whatever it was
in the setting and we think and this is
kind of like Ryan Smith's Precision
Psychiatry work you'll see a ton of
things like this it's like and people
who had this or this categorization or
this or that continuous
variable here was the correlation or the
regression between our inference about
this parameter and whether or not they
were diagnosed this way and here's the T
test and it um looks like something that
you'd find in a paper in other words
supporting an empirical claim being part
of a fabric of evidence about an
empirical
system rather than just having a
hypothetical
GM and then speculating like it could be
this way or it could be that
wayc I mean and until you parameterize
it and especially fit of data because it
usually
could so kind of like a six and little
bit of a Jimmy Hendrick
thing okay all
right thank you fellas see you
um next time see you next week bye bye
thank you byebye